Sean, Kuan-Hsuan Liao



• github.com/seankhliao
• +44 7506372271

● seankhliao.com☑ sean@liao.dev

Infrastructure / platform engineer with a penchant for programming. I build and maintain the internal platforms for product engineers, and work with them to design and implement features in a cloud native environment. I work with teams to ensure their applications are operationally ready to deliver a fast and reliable experience to our customers

Skills

Platforms: AWS, GCP, Kubernetes, ArgoCD, Istio

Application Delivery: Terraform, Docker, Helm, Github Actions, CircleCl, Jenkins, Ansible

Observability: OpenTelemetry, Datadog, Prometheus, ElasticSearch, PagerDuty, FireHydrant, Rootly

Programming: Go (Golang), Python, Shell/Bash

Experience

Infrastructure / Senior Site Reliability Engineer

October 2024 – present

Circle Internet Financial

London, UK

- Maintaining high uptime access to blockchain networks via self hosted (AWS EKS/EC2) nodes
- Investigate and remediate performance bottlenecks across applications (Go / Java) and databases
- Ensure consistency and correctness in data retrieved from distributed / decentralized systems
- General AWS / Kubernetes / GCP infrastructure modernization (e.g. Cloud WAN) and governance
- Internal developer tooling standardization and simplification

Infrastructure / Site Reliability Engineer

June 2022 – September 2024

London, UK

- Technical design and implementation of our Kubernetes cloud re-platforming
- Onboarded incident response vendor for more streamlined incident procedures across the company
- Implemented tooling for SLOs and consulted with teams to raise adoption and reduce alerting fatigue
- Designed and implemented a replatforming of logging (Fluentd/Elastic) and metrics (Prometheus/Grafana) onto Datadog via OpenTelemetry and Vector.
- Maintainer of libraries shared between all Go services
- Worked with open source projects (Dex, OpenTelemetry) to upstream internal improvements
- Additional duties: managing GCP, AWS, K8s, Kyverno, CircleCI, Teleport, Istio, PagerDuty, Postgres/Redis, Backstage

Site Reliability Engineer

March 2022 - June 2022

Deloitte

Snyk

London, UK

• Spearheaded a multi cloud initiative (AWS, GCP) for Deloitte's SaaS product lines.

Infrastructure / Site Reliability Engineer

October 2020-10 - March 2022

De Bijenkorf

Amsterdam, Netherlands

- Standardized and secured Jenkins build pipelines for all services written in JS/TS and Java/Kotlin
- Adopted GitOps with ArgoCD and promoted Continuous Deployment across engineering teams
- Brought the majority of our GCP presence under IaC / terraform.

- Stabilized our logging (Fluentd/Logstash/Elastic) and metrics (Prometheus/Grafana) deployments
- Introduced distributed tracing via auto-instrumentation with OpenTelemetry for Node/JVM services to identify bottlenecks and slowdowns.
- Additional duties: managing GCP, K8s, Postgres/MySQL, OpsGenie, Kafka, and VM deployments with Ansible

Education

MSc, Security and Network Engineering University of Amsterdam

2019 – 2020 Amsterdam, Netherlands

BBA, Information ManagementNational Taiwan University

2014 – 2018 Taipei, Taiwan

Extracurriculars

Go (programming language)

2019 – present

- Standard library code reviewer
- Go project issue triage

seankhliao.com/blog

• Notes on tech, in public so it may help someone (including the author in the future)